

# Patrick A. Jain-Taylor

San Jose, CA • (508) 565-8116 • patrick.andrew.taylor@gmail.com

# Cloud Architect | DevOps Engineer











Professional Cloud Architect and DevOps Engineer with 10+ years of experience in Information Technology in Financial & Mental Health Services. Skilled in Amazon Web Services, Terraform, Kubernetes, Python, and Networking. Strong focus on leadership, team building, and organizational advancement. How can I help?

Contact me

# **Experience**

# Lyra Health

Senior DevOps Engineer • Jul. 2022 - Present

Driving initiatives to standardize our cloud deployments, zero-trust network access, and DevOps best practices for the broader organization.

- Leading initiative to migrate away from our legacy zero-trust network access (ZTNA) solution to Banyan Security ZTNA, and now support 600 services across 2000 internal users using this platform.
- Deployed AWS Control Tower in our AWS Organization to deploy new AWS accounts with necessary security controls & governance, deploy well-architected solutions to our accounts using Account Factory for Terraform, and support future initiatives to fan out our existing applications into dedicated account stacks.

- Mentoring junior & mid-level colleagues through dedicated 1-on-1 time, scheduled office hours, and a bi-weekly show & tell event for all DevOps members to demonstrate their work to the team and critical stakeholders.
- Providing architectural & engineering support for internal security trainings with phishing simulations, including the management of Well-Architected ACM, ELB, IAM, Route 53, ACM, SES, VPC, and WAF services.
- Designing a global cloud network using AWS Network Manager, to reduce our reliance on VPC peering, ensure reachability of resources across regions, analyze & enforce least-privileged access between resources, and manage IP space effectively as we scale.

# Eaton Vance Management, a Morgan Stanley company

Cloud Architect, Core Services • Jan. 2019 — Jun. 2022

Subject matter expert on all things cloud, leading efforts in architecting, engineering, and operating in AWS.

- Transformed Core Services team from an ad-hoc, collaborative pod to an 11 member Agile team of engineers, while serving as team leader and architect.
- Designed Terraform account vending machine & multi-region landing zone for 60+ AWS accounts across the organization, reducing the lead time on new accounts from multiple days to 1 hour, while ensuring a consistent & compliant environment for each application team.
- Architected & deployed infrastructure for 70+ public websites using infrastructure-as-code and automated deployment pipelines, while shifting responsibility "left" to the development team.
- Designed pull- & push-based logging mechanisms for various AWS logs types to Splunk, eliminating cross-account replication cost & duplicate log retention, with charge back to the application teams.
- Responsible for templatization & design of 150+ module Terraform service catalog, with the goal of shifting "left" of infrastructure-as-code to developers. These include actively-maintained READMEs, semantic versioned releases, and backward compatibility for Terraform & provider version updates.
- Leveraged private & public Route 53 Hosted Zones and AWS Certificate Manager to address growing sprawl & cost of our manual certificate generation & rotation process, reducing lead time by 2 weeks and cost by \$1000+ for each certificate. Developers deploy a single Terraform module to secure & resolve their workloads from on-premises and, if necessary, from the public Internet.
- Modularized our multi-region core networking architecture, including edge web traffic inspection, load balancer sandwiching, and inter- & intra-VPC networking, to

- ensure a secure network at the edge while also ensuring new accounts can be accessed both on-premises and within AWS with little administrative action.
- Designed, secured, and automated a multi-environment Snowflake organization, to facilitate data sharing between internal and external stakeholders, with disaster recovery and support for multiple regions built in.

### **Eaton Vance Management**

Network Automation Engineer • Oct. 2017 — Jan. 2019

Focused on automating traditional enterprise networking infrastructure with Python scripting and Ansible playbooking.

- Designed network solutions and maintain service levels across 20 datacenters and remote offices.
- Introduced end-to-end workflow automation via Ansible and Python to infrastructure teams & management.
- Led liaising with engineers & business stakeholders to integrate acquisition networks.
- Drove efforts to standardize network infrastructure, and implement operations training for junior engineers.
- Worked with network visibility vendors to produce single pane-of-glass for identifying network pain points.

### SS&C Technologies

Network Engineer • Oct. 2013 — Oct. 2017

Graduated from part-time site-to-site VPN & firewall administration to full-time design & deployment of resilient networks, serving as primary point-of-contact for 80+ branch office and datacenters.

### **Columbia University**

Various Roles, CU Information Technology (CUIT) • Sept. 2012 — May. 2014

## **General Dynamics**

Intern • May. 2013 — Aug. 2013

# **Providence College**

Various Roles, PC Information Technology (PCIT) & Ghana Sustainable Aid Project (GSAP) • Sept. 2010 — Aug. 2012

# **Certification**

### **Terraform Associate**

Hashicorp • 2020

### **AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate**

Amazon Web Services • 2019

# **Programming with Python**

Codecademy • 2018

# **CCNA Routing & Switching**

Cisco • 2015

# **Education**

# **Columbia University**

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering • 2012 — 2014

# **Providence College**

Bachelor of Arts, Pre-Engineering • 2009 − 2012

# **Technologies**

#### **Amazon Web Services**

Auto Scaling, Backup, Certificate Manager, CloudFormation, CloudFront, CloudWatch Logs, Config, Control Tower, Direct Connect, DynamoDB, EBS, ECR, ECS, EKS, ELB, EventBridge, IAM, Kinesis Data Streams & Firehose, KMS, Lambda, PrivateLink, RDS, Route 53, Route 53 Resolver, S3, Security Groups, Secrets Manager, SNS, SQS, Step Functions, Transit Gateway, VPC, WAF

#### **Third-Party Cloud Services**

Artifactory, Bridgecrew, CloudHealth, Datadog, Nexus, Opal, Prisma, Snowflake, Sonatype, Splunk, Sumo Logic, Wiz

### Infrastructure as Code & Configuration Management

Terraform, CloudFormation, Ansible, Chef

#### **Containerization & Orchestration**

Docker, Kubernetes

#### **Continuous Integration & Continuous Delivery**

Github Actions, GitLab Runner, Jenkins

#### **Programming Languages**

Python, Bash/ZSH

### **Agile Technologies**

Atlassian Jira & Confluence

### **Networking**

Cisco, Juniper, Aruba, Palo Alto Networks, Netskope, Banyan

# **Associations**

# **Hack.Diversity**

Mentor • 2021 - 2024

Hack Diversity is a talent provider of Black & Latinx technologists, supporting underrepresented talent with a yearly fellowship and incubator program. I serve in a mentor role to Hack fellows, and provide education in cloud technologies.